Guide to the George W. Rafter papers, 1872-1920
Rafter, George W. papers, 1872-1920
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George W. Rafter Papers, 1872-1920
4383
George W. Rafter, 1851-1907.
2.2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, publications, photographs, genealogical materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, writings, and publications relating to civil engineering; some personal and family correspondence; photographs; and genealogical materials.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
George W. Rafter studied at Cornell University and served as a civil engineer in Rochester, N.Y. and elsewhere. He designed sewage disposal plants in a number of communities in western New York; worked for the State of New York on the problem of river control, moveable bridges, and high masonry dams; made surveys and estimates for a ship canal from Lake Ontario through Oneida Lake down the Mohawk to the Hudson River; and after 1900 engaged in private consulting practice. He was sole or joint author of some 175 books and papers in addition to innumerable professional reports.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, writings, and publications relating to civil engineering; some personal and family correspondence; photographs; and genealogical materials. Also includes Report of the Board of Engineers on Deep Waterways between the Great Lakes and the Atlantic Tide Waters, Dec. 7, 1900, volume 2 and atlas (141 folded maps and profiles).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rafter, Geo. W. (George W.), b. 1851.; United States. Board of Engineers on Deep Waterways.
Subjects:
Civil engineering.; Inland navigation--United States.; Canals--United States.; Civil engineers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Published work
  - House of Representatives: Report of the Board of Engineers on Deep Waterways Between the Great Lakes and the Atlantic Tide Waters, Atlas ( 1900 ) (Box 1)
- Series II. Volumes by Rafter
  - Mechanics of Ventilation ( 1878 ) (Box 1)
  - Mechanics of Ventilation: Revised Second Edition ( 1896 ) (Box 1)
  - The Treatment of Septic Sewage ( 1904 ) (Box 1)
  - Sewage Disposal in the United States ( 1894 ) (Box 1)
  - Hydrology of the State of New York ( 1905 ) (Box 1)
  - Volume XIII: Special Report on Water Supply of Proposed Deep Water Ways Connecting the Great Lakes with Tide Water: Part II ( 1900 ) (Box 1)
- Series III. Correspondence
  - "Special"--Letters, receipt: 7 items: 1872-1908 (Box 1)
  - A: 1877-1880, 7 items (Box 1)
  - B: 1877-1883, 36 items (Box 1)
  - C-D: 1878-1882, 7 items (Box 1)
  - F-G: 1878-1882, 16 items (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Ethel Rafter, 1895-1901 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - George Rafter, 1890-1907 (Box 3)
- Series IV. Miscellaneous
  - Unititled--Price list of scientific books comprising the library of the late George W. Rafter for sale by J. R. Williams: 2nd edition, June 1, 1908 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings and bound volumes of manuscripts and letters (vols. 3, 16-19, 21-23, 30) (Box 2)
  - Publications by GWR; scrapbook of newspaper clippings (Box 3)
  - Photographs (Box 3)
  - Misc. items (Box 3)
  - broadside, "Interamerican School of Spanish", 1956 (Folder 1)